IRFAN WAHYU RAMADHANI

 $Semarang, Jawa Tengah \parallel +6285875177129 \parallel \underline{Iramadhani679@gmail.com} \parallel \underline{www.linkedin.com/in/irfan-wahyu-ramadhani} \parallel \underline{https://github.com/irfanwahyr}$

SUMMARY

Irfan Wahyu Ramadhani is a final year student from Dian Nuswantoro University majoring in Informatics Engineering. Interest in the role of data and website. Proficient in SQL, Python, Excel, and Data Visualization Tools in data science as well as React, Express, Flutter on websites. Have experience some Data Science projects, and also some Full Stack Website Projects. I learned skills that made it easier. I want to join a team and work together continuously to achieve results amidst failures and setbacks. I am a person who is able to make decisions quickly and correctly, even when the situation is critical or in bad circumstances pressure.

EDUCATION

Universitas Dian Nuswantoro

Informatics Engineering

September 2021 - Now

- Current GPA: 3.82/4.00.
- Undergraduate thesis topic: Forecasting Air Quality Index Using Long Short-Term Memory.

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Participant

Course-Net Indonesia – MSIB batch 6

February 2024 – June 2024

- Completed 3 mini projects from Course-Net Indonesia, namely a simple algorithm project, a project for classifying safe passengers using Titanic ship data, and a regression case for taxi passengers.
- Create 1 final project related to cases of customer churn on credit cards. starting from problem analysis, to model evaluation to classify customers who churn.
- Completed all class material starting from introduction to python, introduction to SQL, advanced SQL, to advanced data science.

Full Stack Website Developer

February 2024 – June 2024

Dian Nuswantoro University - Internship

- Create back-end design of the Dian Nuswantoro University laboratory lending website.
- Designing the front-end of the Dian Nuswantoro University laboratory lending website.
- Designing a data relationship system on the database used.
- The laboratory lending website is used as a means of borrowing for all related activities, such as substitute classes and university events.

Dicoding Academy

December 2022 – June 2024

 $Dicoding-Independent\ Learning$

- Complete the classes contained in the coding according to the deadline. starting from classes learning python, data analysis, to data science experts.
- Complete the classes contained in the coding according to the deadline. Starting from learning javascript for front-end, and also API concept with back-end javascript framework.
- Make many projects as a requirement to complete the class. starting from data analysis, NLP machine learning projects, image processing, to Time Series starting from beginner to advanced classes.

Research Collaborator as Data Scientist

September 2023 – February 2024

IDSS Udinus – Independent Internship

- Conducting research on air quality index forecasting and Publishing a journal in SINTA 3.
- Assisting a professor's research and contributing to the creation of a Q3 journal.

PROJECT

Credit Card Churn Prediction (Data Science Course-Net Indonesia)

June 2024

Predictions related to high customer churn on credit cards and analysis of the factors that cause them, namely
focusing on analysis related to transaction factors from customers, and creating a prediction model (<u>link</u>).

Online Reservation laboratory

June 2024

(Full-Stack Website Internship)

Fullstack project online laboratory lending website at Dian Nuswantoro University which includes design, initialization and implementation. For Front-End (link), and for Back-End (link).

Student Performance Prediction (Data Science Dicoding Academy)

May 2024

Predicting student performance related to the number of students who drop out by focusing on predictions based on students' financial conditions, where the creation starts from problem analysis, creating dashboards for data analysis, to modeling and deploying for predictions (link).

Employee Attrition Prediction

(Data Science Dicoding Academy)

Predictions related to the high rate of employee resignations and analysis of the causes, namely focusing on analysis related to age and gender of employees, creating dashboards for analysis and developing prediction models (link).

Bookshelf-Notes-API

April 2024

(Back-End Dicoding Academy)

Created an API for an online bookshelf system that implements CRUD concepts (link).

Bookshelf-Notes

February 2024

(Front-End Dicoding Academy)

Create a dynamic display related to online bookshelves that can apply the CRUD concept and the concept of moving books based on reading status (link).

Telegram Bot

January 2024

(Independent Project)

Telegram bot for conversations, downloading music or videos from YouTube, and other features (link).

Image Classification for Shoe, Shoes, and Sandal

December 2023

(Machine Learning Dicoding Academy)

. Classification models for rock-paper-scissors images (link).

Sentiment Analys for Emotion Detection from Tweet Text

December 2023

(machine Learning Dicoding Academy)

Analyst sentiment related to Twitter users' emotions based on their tweets, namely classification based on labels from users' tweet text (link)

Image Classification for Rock, Paper, Scissor (Machine Learning Dicoding Academy)

November 2023

. Classification models for rock-paper-scissors images (link).

Analysis of Bicycle Rentals based on Time and Season (Data Analysis Dicoding Academy)

October 2023

Dashboard for analyzing data on bicycle borrowing in certain seasons and times which is created by grouping and retrieving some data for analysis to see insight into bicycle borrowing (link)

SKILLSET

HardSkill

- Familiar with complex query using SQL and able to using MYSQL and SQL Server.
- Familiar with front-end website framework like ReactJS and Flutter, and also back-end website framework like Laravel and ExpressJS.
- Familiar with Python programming for exploratory data analysis, preprocessing, and build data modelling.
- Familiar with CRUD, OOP, Clean Code concepts and Postman.
- Able to using data visualization tools such as Tableau, Streamlit, Metabase and Looker Studio.
- Familiar with Github, Google Colab, Visual Studio Code, and Microsoft Office.

SoftSkill

- Ability to manage time well in various situations.
- Good analytical skills to be able to find the right solution.
- Have a desire to always learn new things

Certification - link